Guide to the Franz R. and Kathryn M. Stenzel Collection of Western American Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Series VI, Bird's-Eye Views (1860-1959), box 52, is organized into eight subseries: British Columbia, California, Colorado, Idaho, Minnesota, Montana, Oregon, and Washington. The subseries are organized alphabetically by city, and then by date. Series VII, Maps (1851-1890), box 53, is organized into two subseries: Oregon and Washington. Within each subseries the maps are organized chronologically. Every bird's-eye view and map in these two series is printed, with the exception of an 1855 manuscript map of Portland by A. B. Hallock.
Series VIII, Other Manuscripts and Papers (1676-1915), box 54, is organized into two subseries: Manuscripts & Ephemera and Photographs. The Manuscripts and Ephemera, which consists of miscellaneous early material from both the east and west coasts, are organized by George Andrews Family Correspondence, John McLoughlin Papers, Dover/Smith Papers, Thomas Smith Documents, Valentine Smith Family Correspondence, Miscellaneous Correspondence, Miscellaneous Documents, Miscellaneous Writings, Miscellaneous Printed Material, and Other Material. This series includes three presidential autographs: Franklin Pierce, James Buchanan, and Abraham Lincoln, all signatures on temporary appointments for Thomas M. Smith as Auditor of the Treasury. A letter from Valentine Smith in Louisville to John Edwards Smith in Durham, New Hampshire, dated 1838 May 28, one of a series of four letters written or received by Valentine Smith, discusses slavery in Kentucky. There are also early deeds of land in Dover, New Hampshire, dated 1676-1717. The Photographs are organized by Western photographs and Other photographs. Western photographers represented here are Charles L. Gillingham (Colorado Springs, Colo.); Crow and Lussier (Portland, Oregon); Eklund Studio (Great Falls, Montana); R. H. Gardiner, Photo (Albina, Oregon); Scherer, Photographer (St. Louis); and Taber (San Francisco).
Oversize, boxes 55-63, broadside folders 1196-1232, artstore folder numbers 1233-1279, and rolled folders 1280-1281, contains material from Series I-VIII, and is organized in box order.
Haida Indians; Indians of North America -- Northwest, Pacific; Indians of North America -- Washington (State); Makah Indians; Pioneers -- Washington (State); Northwest, Pacific -- Pictorial works; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Drawings (visual works); Engravings (prints); Etchings (prints); Lithographs; Oil paintings (visual works); Pastels (visual works); Watercolors (paintings); Alden, James Madison, 1834-1922; Boughton, George Henry, 1834-1905; Burbank, E. A. (Elbridge Ayer), 1858-1949; Elswa, Johnny Kit; Flagg, James Montgomery, 1877-1960; Gifford, Sanford Robinson, 1823-1880; Johnson, Eastman, 1824-1906; Kehoe, Joseph, 1890-1959; Kleiber, Hans, 1887-1967; McEntee, Jervis, 1828-1891; McIlwraith, William Forsyth; Moser, James Henry, 1854-1913; Paxson, E. S., 1852-1919; Pease, Lute, 1869-1963; Rockwell, Cleveland, 1837-1907; Stuart, James Everett; Swan, James G., 1818-1900; Toft, Peter Peterson; Whittredge, Worthington, 1820-1910; Winter, Daniel; Wood, Charles Erskine Scott, 1852-1944
- James Madison Alden Artwork and Associated Material, 1728-1894; Series I; 5.36; (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, James Madison Alden Artwork and Associated Material, is organized into two subseries: Artwork and Associated Material. The artwork is organized by California Views, Columbia River and Related Views, Fraser River and Related Views, and Other Views. Within each section the works are arranged by date. Manuscript captions appear on each artwork's verso except where noted.
  - ARTWORK
    - California Views
      - "The 'Deadman's Island' Pedro Bay Calif." Watercolor, 17.5 x 25 cm., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Rough pencil sketches on verso
      - "Foot of Tamel Pais (or Table Mountain) with Widow Reed's Rancho near San Francisco Bay, Cala." Watercolor, 24 x 33.8 cm., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Note on verso: "This mt. is said to be the Devil's abode!" "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso
      - "Rancho & Valley Santa Cruz Island - California." Watercolor, 17.5 x 26.2 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso
      - "Saucelito Cove - Bay of San Francisco." Watercolor, 23.9 x 30.7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
        "Catherine" written on lower right of verso. "April 12 1857" written on lower left of verso
      - "'Shanghai Rancho' near Saucelito Cala. - San Francisco Bay." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.7 cm., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        "Mary" written on lower right of verso. "Apr. 18/57" written on lower left of verso
      - "Sulphur Springs near Sta. Barbara Cala." Watercolor, 30.6 x 23.7 cm., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Signed. "Vernon" written on lower right of verso
      - "Valley of Montecito near Sta. Barbara, Cala." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.7 cm., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso. "April 10/57" written on lower left of verso
      - "Isomi (or Clear Lake) View from near Kachinhama[?]." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.7 cm., 1856 Apr (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - "Cañon - S. part San Clemente Island, California." Watercolor, 26 x 18.5 cm., 1856 Jun (Box 1, Folder 9)
        "G.L. Dorsey" and "Vernon" written on verso
      - "Camp at Clear Lake, California." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.7 cm., 1857 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        "Catherine" written on lower right of verso
      - "Clear Lake, California." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.5 cm., 1857 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso. "fin. Aug. 1858" written on lower left of verso
      - "Mt. 'Conoktai' Clear Lake, California, sunset." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.5 cm., 1857 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - "Sacramento River, Cala. (Mt. Diablo in the Distance) looking down." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.7 cm., 1858 Mar (Box 1, Folder 13)
        "Mrs. Parham" written on lower right of verso
      - "In Geyser Cañon, Cala." Watercolor, 23.9 x 30.7 cm., 1858 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - "'Bridal Veil' from the foot of El-Capitan. Yo-semite Valley, Cala." Watercolor, 30.5 x 23.6 cm., 1859 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #7" written on upper right of verso
      - "Domes Yo Semite Cala." Watercolor, 29.9 x 45.3 cm., 1859
        Signed. "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #12" written on upper right of verso
      - "Marble Cave. Mariposa Co. California." Watercolor, 31.2 x 24.2 cm., 1859 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Signed
      - "Nevada Fall & Cañon. YoSemite - Cala." Watercolor, 30 x 45 cm., 1859
        Signed. "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #10" written on upper right of verso
      - "Suspension Flume. Cañon near Murphy's Diggings, Cala." Watercolor, 23.9 x 30.6 cm., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "The Three Brothers. 4000 ft. high with distant view of the big falls. Valley of the Yo-Semite." Watercolor, 23.8 x 30.6 cm., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - "Tuolumne R. Cala. (view at Jacksonville.)" Watercolor, 23.8 x 30.6 cm., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - "'Tuscan Springs' Cañon, Cala." Watercolor, 23.8 x 30.6 cm., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - "Waterfall opposite the 'Bridal Veil' Yo-semite Valley Cala." Watercolor, 30.9 x 23.6 cm., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 21)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #6" written on upper right of verso
      - "Bridal Veil, Yosemite Valley." Watercolor, 30.7 x 23.8 cm., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - "From Pt. Boneta - Entrance San Francisco Bay." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.7 cm., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Columbia River and Related Views
      - "Columbia R. Oregon - opposite Fort Vancouver." Pencil drawing with wash, 17.9 x 26.8 cm., 1854 Jul (Box 2, Folder 24)
        Signed. Manuscript caption below image. Pencil sketch on verso titled "Entrance to Deception Passage from Whidbey Isld. 10 Sept. 1854." Preliminary sketch for watercolor entitled "Entrance to Deception Passage, Rosario Straits, W.T. Mt. Baker in the distance" (folder 27)
      - "Old Astoria, from Leonard & Green's Store, Astor's Point." Pencil drawing, 18 x 26.7 cm., 1854 Aug 4 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        Signed. Manuscript caption below image
      - "Indian Village, Port Townsend, Washington Ter." Pencil drawing with pen-and-ink, 18 x 27 cm. 1854 Aug 26 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        Manuscript caption below image. Pencil drawing on verso titled "'Whatcom' Bellingham Bay Aug 10 1854."
      - "Entrance to Deception Passage, Rosario Straits, W.T. Mt. Baker in the distance." Watercolor, 23.9 x 33.6 cm., 1854 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        Signed. Manuscript caption below image. Pencil sketch with wash on verso of a road with trees and a mountain in the distance. "Mary" written on lower right of verso. See also preliminary sketch in folder 24
      - "Graveyard in woods - Astoria, Oregon." Watercolor, 16 x 26.2 cm., [1854?] (Box 2, Folder 28)
        Note on verso: "Here are some of the old pioneers of Oregon buried in the forest near the village of Astoria. The two graves near each other are those of a U.S. soldier & sailor who died here some years since." "Vernon" written on lower left of verso. See also preliminary sketch in folder 29
      - "Mill, at Bellingham Bay, W.T." Pen-and-ink drawing over pencil, 18 x 27 cm., 1854 (Box 2, Folder 29)
        Signed. "U.S.S. Active" above Alden's initials and date in lower right corner. Watercolor sketch on verso titled "Grave Yard near Astoria OC." Preliminary sketch for "Graveyard in woods - Astoria, Oregon" (folder 28)
      - "Near Bellingham Bay, Washington Territory." Watercolor, 17.6 x 26.3 cm. (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - "New Astoria, Oregon." Pencil drawing, 18 x 53.9 cm., 1854
        Signed. Manuscript caption below image. Pencil drawing on verso of "'Switzler's Ferry' on the Columbia opposite Ft. Vancouver"
        Stored in: Oversize box 55, folder 1081
      - "Old Astoria - Columbia R. from the beach near the 'Union House.'" Pen-and-ink drawing with wash, 18.2 x 27 cm., 1854 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        Manuscript caption below image
      - "Columbia R. above Cascades - looking down." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.6 cm., 1857 Jul (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - "Below The Dalles, Columbia River." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.4 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - "Cascades - Columbia R. below the Rapids." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.6 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - "'Cathedral' 2500 ft. high. Columbia R." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.5 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - "Columbia R. - below The Dalles." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.4 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 36)
        "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso. "Jan. 20/58" written on lower left of verso
      - "Columbia R. - below The Dalles." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.5 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 37)
        Watercolor of a river crossed out in pencil on verso. "Mrs. Parham" written on lower right of verso
      - "Columbia R. Looking down fr. below the Dalles cm. (Box 3, Folder 38)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #2" written on upper right of verso. "March 28, 1859" written on lower left of verso
      - "Columbia R. on the Cascade Portage." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.5 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 39)
        "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso. "Sep 25/57" written on lower left of verso
      - "Fort Dalles, Columbia River, looking down." Three panoramic watercolors, 23.6 x 91.5 cm., 1857
        Stored in: Broadside folder 1196
      - "From Upper Cascades looking up Columbia R." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.5 cm. (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - "Grand Rapids. Cascades of the Columbia." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.5 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - "Mt. Hood fr. mouth Dog River - Columbia River above Cascades." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.5 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 42)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #4" written on upper right of verso
      - "Obelisk Rk Columbia R. below Cascades." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.6 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - "Rapids. Columbia R." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.6 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - "Upper Cascades, Columbia River." Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.6 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - "View on Cascade Portage - Columbia R." Watercolor, 23.7 x 30.8 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 46)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #1" written on upper right of verso
      - "Youngs River Falls, Oregon." Watercolor, 35 x 25 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 47)
        Watercolor of river in front of mountains on verso crossed out. "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #9" written on upper right of verso
      - "Youngs R. Oregon." Watercolor, 23.7 x 30.6 cm., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 48)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #5" written on upper right of verso
      - "Below Cascade Rapids height 4 to 600 ft." Watercolor, 23.7 x 30.5 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 49)
        Verso has unfinished watercolor sketch of two ships. "Catherine" written on lower right of verso
      - "Mouth of White Salmon R. (above Cascades.)" Watercolor, 23.5 x 30.5 cm. (Box 3, Folder 50)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #3" written on upper right of verso
    - Fraser River and Related Views
      - "Cove in 'Matia Group' Gulf of Georgia N.W.B." Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.8 cm., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - "Fraser's R. 15 miles below Ft. Langley." Watercolor, 23.7 x 30.6 cm., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 52)
        "Mrs. Parham" written on lower right of verso. "Feb. 25 1859" written on lower left of verso
      - "On Fraser's River looking up from near Mouth Chiloneyuck River British Columbia." Watercolor, 23.7 x 30.7 cm., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 53)
        Chilliwack River. "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso
      - "Looking up Fraser R." Watercolor, 23.7 x 32.9 cm., [1859] (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - "Mouth Harrison R. a branch of Fraser R." Watercolor, 23.8 x 30.6 cm., 1859 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - "Boundary between U.S. and B.C." Watercolor and pastel, 27.2 x 56.2 cm., 1860
        Signed. "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #13" written on center of verso
      - "Chief Mountain Lake Rocky Mountains Lat. 49." Watercolor, 29.5 x 42.5 cm., 1860 Sep (Box 4, Folder 56)
        "Katherine" written on verso
      - "Looking up Kootenay River North of the 49th Parallel British Columbia." Watercolor, 30.5 x 45 cm., 1860
        Signed. "Katherine" written on verso
      - "Fraser R. Camp a.m." Watercolor, 23.8 x 33 cm., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 57)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #8" written on upper right of verso
      - "Great Stone Face" Fraser R. 9 miles below Hope." Watercolor, 33 x 23.7 cm., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 58)
        "Vernon" written on lower right of verso
      - "Indian village above Fort Hope." Watercolor, 23.7 x 33 cm. (Box 4, Folder 59)
        "G.L. Dorsey" and "Mary" written on verso
      - "Looking up Fraser - to above Harrison R." Watercolor, 23.8 x 33 cm., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - "Nanaimo River, Vancouvers Island." Watercolor, 23.9 x 34.2 cm on sheet 30.4 x 45.4 cm. (Box 4, Folder 61)
        "Collection of Mary Dorsey Adams #11" written on upper right of verso
      - "Seabird Bar - Fraser R. looking down." Watercolor, 23.7 x 32.9 cm., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 62)
        "Vernon" written on bottom right of verso
    - Other Views
      - "On Deer Island, Coast of Maine." Pencil drawing, 15.3 x 24.2 cm., 1851 Sep (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - [Unidentified scene of river running through a mountain range.] Watercolor 17.5 x 25.3 cm., 1852 (Box 4, Folder 64)
        "Mary Dorsey" written on bottom right of verso
      - "Ancient House, Stow Mts." Pencil drawing, 21.5 x 23.5 cm., 1853 Feb 2 (Box 4, Folder 65)
        Signed. Manuscript caption below image. "Near Stow Centre Ms, Rd. from Stow to Acton" written on verso
      - "W.B. McMurtrie USStr Active." Watercolor and color pencil, 21.5 x 16.3 cm., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - "The Wayside Inn Sudbury Masstts." Watercolor, 21.2 x 35.9 cm., 1870 (Box 4, Folder 67)
        Caption at lower left of watercolor. "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso
      - "Old Farm House, Stow Massts. 12 to 2.15 p.m. Sep. 9 1874. Warm & pleasant day, some clouds." Watercolor, 25 x 36 cm., 1874 Sep 9 (Box 4, Folder 68)
        Signed. Manuscript notes on color in watercolor on verso
      - "My Cottage at Brant Rock, Masstts." Watercolor, 23 x 45 cm., 1874 (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - "The 'Tate House': Strandwater Village near Portland Maine. Thurs. Aug. 10, 1876, 11 a.m. (very warm)." Watercolor, 24.8 x 35.3 cm., 1876 Aug 10 (Box 4, Folder 70)
        "Jeanne" written on lower right of verso. Abbreviated caption at lower left of recto
      - "Deserted Farmhouse. Fitzwilliam N.H. Thurs. Aug 1877 fin 12.45 pm." Watercolor, 24.9 x 36 cm. on sheet 27.7 x 37.7 cm., 1877 Aug (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - "At Stow Mass. July 25, 1884 fin 5.30 p.m. sultry & cloudy." Watercolor, 27.7 x 46.6 cm., 1884 Jul 25 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - [Harbor scene.] Watercolor, 28.6 x 45.5 cm.
  - ASSOCIATED MATERIAL
    - Dorsey, Vernon I., San Francisco, Calif. to Richard B. Dorsey, Baltimore, Maryland, 1851 Dec 15
    - Land grant from Charles, Lord and Proprietary of the Province of Maryland to John Howard. Manuscript on vellum, with original seal attached, framed, 1728 Feb 27
      Seal of the first Lord Baltimore
- James G. Swan Artwork and Associated Material, 1852-1911; Series II; 9.18; (7 boxes)
  Series II, James G. Swan Artwork and Associated Material, is organized into five subseries: Artwork, Correspondence, Writings, Printed Material, Photographs, and Miscellaneous Documents. The Artwork is organized into Works by Swan and Works by Johnny Kit Elswa, and within each section is organized topically. The Correspondence is organized into Incoming, Outgoing, and Third Party Correspondence. The Writings are organized into Writings by Swan and Writings by Others.
  - ARTWORK
    - Works by Swan
      - Botanicals
        - "Raspberry." Watercolor, 19.4 x 13.5 cm., 1854 Jun (Box 5, Folder 73)
        - "Arbutus Uva Uvai." Watercolor, 19.4 x 12.7 cm., [1854?]
        - "Clarkia." Watercolor, 19.4 x 13 cm., 1854 Jul
          Watercolor of maple leaf on verso
        - "Que uts quenim - Queniult." Watercolor of flowering plant, 20.4 x 14.4 cm., [1854 ?] (Box 5, Folder 74)
        - "Wild pea." Watercolor, 20.4 x 14.1 cm., 1854 Jun
        - "Dicentra formosa." Watercolor, 20.4 x 13.9 cm., n.y. Apr 3
        - [Five plants: salmon berry, cammass (2), sallal, and konkiwhi(?)] Color pencil drawing, 19.1 x 24 cm., 1859 Jun 5 (Box 5, Folder 75)
        - "Hull iar ka bupt - (makah). The shrub used by the Indians to make the discs or wheels used in playing the gambling game of La Hull." Pencil drawing with wash, 17 x 24 cm. (Box 5, Folder 76)
        - "Napea[?]" Watercolor of flowering plant, 20.4 x 14.2 cm., 1854 Jul (Box 5, Folder 77)
        - "Trillium." Watercolor, 20.4 x 13.9 cm., n.y. Mar 10
        - "Solomons seal." Watercolor, 20.4 x 13.7 cm., [1854 ?]
        - "Sallal." Watercolor, 16.6 x 11.6 on sheet 17.9 x 15.2 cm., 1873 Jun (Box 5, Folder 78)
        - "Salmon Berry, Wake Robin, and species of cress found at Neeah Bay." Watercolor, 23 x 18 cm., [1861 Apr] (Box 5, Folder 79)
        - "Service berry." Watercolor, 25 x 17.8 cm., 1879 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 80)
        - "Species of fungus found at Shoalwater Bay, Oregon. Watercolor, 12 x 19.3 cm., 1852 Dec (Box 5, Folder 81)
        - "Trillium Grandifolium 'Wake Robin.' Watercolor, 35 x 25.2 cm., 1879 May (Box 5, Folder 82)
        - "Yellow lily. Shoalwater Bay." Watercolor, 19.4 x 13 cm., 1854 Jun (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - Ethnographic Objects
        - "Ancient Post at Yakh village, north end of Graham Island, Queen Charlotte Islands, B.C." Pencil drawing, 25.5 x 17.9 cm., 1883 Jul (Box 5, Folder 84)
        - "Ancient Totem column embedded in a spruce tree found at ancient village of Chathl in E. coast North Island." Pencil drawing, 25.5 x 18 cm., 1883 Aug 11 (Box 5, Folder 85)
        - [Canoe drawings, three on one page.] Pencil drawing, 26.5 x 19 cm., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 86)
        - "Haida canoe as seen at Massett Queen Charlotte Island." Pencil drawing, 18 x 24.5 cm., 1883 Jul (Box 5, Folder 87)
        - "Haida Indians of Queen Charlotte Island B.C. Showing their style of tattooing. Port Townsend." Pen-and-ink drawing over pencil, 24.8 x 19.5 cm., 1879 Feb 9 (Box 5, Folder 88)
        - [Headdress, bow and arrows, and the egg of a skate.] Pencil drawing with colored pencil, 18.1 x 23 cm., 1859 Oct (Box 5, Folder 89)
        - "Heraldic and totemic column or Picturegraph in front of house at Skidegate QC Island, BC." Pencil drawing, 25.4 x 18 cm., 1883 Aug (Box 5, Folder 90)
        - "Heraldic column of Kioosta village, Parry Passage, Queen Charlotte Islands." Pencil drawing, 25.5 x 18 cm., 1883 Aug (Box 6, Folder 91)
        - "House and carved column of Anneth las[?] a chief at Massett Charlotte Islands B.C." Pencil drawing, 35.1 x 25.3 cm., 1883 Jul 19 (Box 6, Folder 92)
        - "Indian implements used among the Makahs at Cape Flattery, W.T." Color pencil drawing, 18 x 23 cm., 1859 Oct 18 (Box 6, Folder 93)
          Accompanied by print of Clyoquot paddle and Halibut hook
        - "Kitchen-sum. Private mark." Painting, using chewed salmon eggs spit into vermilion, and ground bituminous coal, 22.8 x 18.1 cm., 1859 Nov 10 (Box 6, Folder 94)
        - "Legend of Koathlkai and his dog." Pencil drawing with wash, 20.8 x 26.8 cm. (Box 6, Folder 95)
          Manuscript description on verso of legends of Koathlkai and the Three Hunters
        - "Legend of the Three Hunters and the Bear." Pencil drawing with wash, 20.9 x 27.1 cm. (Box 6, Folder 96)
        - "Mortuary column, Masset. Erected to memory of Edinso of Kaigani son of Edinso, Chief of Masset, Queen Charlotte Island, B.C." Pencil drawing, 35.1 x 25.2 cm., 1883 Aug 3 (Box 6, Folder 97)
        - "Saddle of whale's blubber." Pencil drawing with wash, 18 x 23 cm., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 98)
          Title from accompanying print of drawing
        - [Seal club.] Pencil drawing with wash, 25.2 x 35.1 cm., 1879 Aug 25 (Box 6, Folder 99)
          Accompanied by a manuscript description of the images on the club
        - [Seal spearheads.] Pencil drawing with wash, 20 x 26.2 cm., [1881] (Box 6, Folder 100)
        - "Nittinat Indians tattoo marks." Pencil drawings, 29.3 x 31.5 cm. and smaller, 1881 Jan 20 (Box 6, Folder 101)
        - [Sketches of the Skookum, half bird and half man "lives in the forest and eats Indians."] Pencil sketches, 29.2 x 15.9 cm., [1873 May ?] (Box 6, Folder 102)
        - [Spearhead.] Pencil drawing, 20 x 31.6 cm., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 103)
          "U.S. Fish Commission" written at top of drawing. Table (incomplete) on verso is titled "A statement showing the number of vessels employed in the fur sealing business at Neah Bay during the season ending June 30, 1880."
        - "Tattoo marks on the back and legs of John Kitkagens." Pencil drawing, 40.6 x 15.8 cm., [1873 May ?] (Box 6, Folder 104)
        - "Tattoo marks." Bottom of plate 4, all of plate 7 from Swan's The Haidah Indians of Queen Charlotte's Islands, British Columbia with a brief description of Their Carvings, Tattoo Designs, Etc., 23.6 x 29.8 cm. and smaller, 1874 (Box 6, Folder 105)
        - "Thunder Bird of the Makahs from the Tamanous board in the house of the late Yellicom or Flattery Jack." Pen-and-ink drawing with color pencil, 18.1 x 23 cm., 1859 Nov 29 (Box 6, Folder 106)
        - "Tomahnawos board at the base of monument over 'Swell' a Makah chief buried at Baadah Pt. Neah Bay W.T." Painting, 18 x 23.4 cm., [1861 Apr ?] (Box 6, Folder 107)
        - "Tomanawos masks used by the Mackah, Nootka & Clyoquot Indians. Wooden dish used by the Mackah Indians. Mackah basket." Painting, pen-and-ink and pencil drawings on one sheet, 18.1 x 23 cm., [1859 ?] (Box 6a, Folder 108)
          Accompanied by print versions of each drawing